# Luiz Felipe de Jesus Falcao

Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada

falcao.lfj@yahoo.com

+1 (672) 513-2641

linkedin.com/in/luizfelipejfalcao

http://www.luizfelipefalcao.com

# **Summary**

Bachelor of Computer Science and passionate about Javascript and its frameworks like ReactJS, I am a front-end web developer with 3+ years of experience that always seeks professional development using this stack.

I currently develop personal projects, in addition to looking for a job opportunity in order to improve my skills and learn more about the world of web development.

My skills include creating Single Page Applications (SPA's) and Landing Pages developing the concepts of componentization nailed by ReactJS. I also use the Firebase database and authenticator for excellent real-time performance, as well as Material-UI and Styled-Components for the stylization of my project.

## **Experience**



## **Brazilian Marine Corps - Software Developer**

Marinha do Brasil

Jan 2018 - Present (4 years 2 months +)

\*\* Frontend Web Developer \*\*

Implementing pages and creating components for seminars held throughout the year which dealt with issues such as Naval Peace Operations carried out by the UN and instructions promoted by the Admiral Sylvio de Camargo Instruction Center.

I have used the following tools:

Javascript (ES6);

ReactJS and NextJS as framework;

CSS and Bootstrap for stylization;

PostgreSQL as database;

Use of Git for version control of our applications;

Jira as workflow and management of SCRUM.

Stack: Javascript, ReactJS, PostgreSQL, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrasp, Git, Jira and VSCode.

\*\* Lua Software Developer \*\*

As a software developer using the Lua programming language and its libraries as IUP, I worked on the maintenance of the SJD (Didactic Games Simulator), maintaining the database and optimizing the simulator performance, creating and updating new elements during the simulation.

Stack: Lua, IUP, PostgreSQL.



## **Brazilian Marine Corps - IT Support Technician**

Marinha do Brasil

Jan 2011 - Jan 2018 (7 years 1 month)

As a support technician for the Marine Armored Battalion (Brazilian Navy), which had more than 70 workstations, I worked in several roles:

- Maintenance and optimization of intranet and internet services using SUSE Linux and Windows Server operating systems.
- Maintenance of workstations, installing and updating the applications used for the workflow;
- Data repository and storage of confidential documents;
- Configuration of several Brazilian Navy's systems, used by that battalion, such as: encrypted messaging systems, e-mail platforms, among others.
- Military technical training for the use of administrative systems.



## **Brazilian Marine Corps**

Marinha do Brasil

Jan 2008 - Jan 2011 (3 years 1 month)

When I joined the Marine Corps of the Brazilian Navy, I served in the Marine Group of Ladário and operated in the most diverse exercises performed by that group.

#### Education



#### Centro Universitário UniCarioca

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science 2013 - 2018

## **Licenses & Certifications**

ReactJS do zero ao avançado na prática - React/Redux - 17,5 horas - Udemy UC-35bc6bc6-bfb9-48f9-a06a-d8fef70457b2/



Cambly Certificate of Accomplishment - 24 hours of English conversation practice with Cambly's native English teachers - Cambly Inc.

ff4cef1d

#### Skills

Front-end Development • Javascript • React.js • Computer Science • Web Development • Responsive Web Design • Software Development • HTML5 • CSS • Git

## **Honors & Awards**

**Amphibious Merit Medal** - Brazilian Navy - Marines Corps

Medal of amphibious merit, honor for the services provided and missions accomplished.